I join I think my question somehow
relates to Yang's question just gonna
read it out so while the c19 crisis
presents a great chance to get people to
question existing institutions and to
deploy new ways of sense-making
it also creates a chance for governments
to introduce lasting authoritarian
measures without resistance as they can
be effective in the current situation so
how can something like decentralized
collective intelligence or game be
gained traction in a time in which
authoritarian measures can be perceived
perceived as a valid fallback option to
weather crisis situations like this yeah
well I think this goes back to that
notion of Kairos I think right now we're
in a situation where things could either
move very well or they can move very
poorly I think the general answer is if
we were on the other side of
authoritarian measures putting being put
in place and it will make it much harder
for us not catastrophic it's not
impossible they'll just make it much
harder and by the way it'll make the
consequences of the shifts more let's
call it energetic so the key right now
is to figure out how can we go about
nudging and influencing the shift that
takes place so as to minimize that and
whatever possible actually maximize the
good side so I'll give you a concrete
example this is really really real like
right now and over the next several days
and near-term weeks significant choices
are being made in the United States and
everywhere else around the world the
choices of large has already been made
in China as I understand it about how
we're gonna go about trying to address
the problem of contact tracing for
example we're testing now there are many
many possible solutions and actually now
come to mind with Ivan Illich there have
always been many solutions around
education we just chose the ones that
were bad there are many solutions to the
question of how do we actually build an
infrastructure that is able to
powerfully effortlessly respond to the
problem domain of these kinds of events
to crises along the viral and viruses
what I would like to see is wisdom being
used in those designs and I don't mean
the
not evilly there are actually people
asking for that you know significant
powerful people are asking for that we
just need to find a way to create space
for it and then bring the right people
in so that we can actually propose
designs that will solve the problem well
for the long term and with not only
without threats to freedom and liberty
and our capacity to communicate in
affected with each other but actually up
gradient that make it better so I think
right now the situation is the the the
die are about to be cast and when it is
incumbent upon us to find a way to put
pressure to create the space to make
sure the good solutions are put in place
if we can find AK one thing so I said if
I there's one thing that comes out of
this that I would like to see be a boom
we have massive shift in the nature of
how we go about supporting the
development of our children if I had one
thing that I would talk about people
just rallying around and just saying no
to would be just short-term mindless
solutions to these problems you know
what it's if I could get people to say I
would prefer I am willing to stay in
quarantine for another six weeks in
exchange for having a good solution to
this problem like a trade off on the
part of the people we demand a good
design we demand this something actually
makes sense in exchange we're not gonna
riot in the streets where I can do crazy
stuff we're okay we will create some
space for this to happen that would be a
wonderful thing I don't know if we can
pull it off because there's a lot of
diverse interest out there and I get it
I mean people who have small businesses
right now are feeling really really put
upon it people who work for a living and
don't have a lot of coverage or feeling
really really put about I understand
that and so there's an urgency to figure
out how to put solutions together you
know so such as is Right Kairos is never
pretty we're right in the middle of a
very messy circumstance and bad things
are happening left and right so we got
to try to figure out how we can get as
smooth as possible to because good
things happen too
[Music]
you